

Contacts

KA-145/23/2, Uttar-Poshcim Para, Khilkhet, Dhaka-1229



nazrulkhan.dk@gmail.com



+8801754730922



Github.com/NobinKhan gitlab.com/nobinkhan



@nobinbd

Hard Skills

- Python Programming
- Amazon web services (AWS)
- ORM & SQL
- Django & Fastapi
- DRF (Django Rest Framework)
- Django GraphQL
- CI/CD Pipeline
- Server Management
- WebSocket & Django-Signal
- Docker & Podman
- Redis & Django-Celery & RMQ

Soft Skills

- Teamwork
- Problem Solving
- Dedicated
- Active Learning
- Leadership Skill
- Creative Thinking

Academic Qualification

BSc in Computer Science and Engineering (2017-Present)

Shanto-Mariam University of Creative Technology

- Excelled in Computer Science coursework and computer labs.
- Provided student tutoring and IT services to 24 classmates.
- President and organizer of Students Who Code coding club.

MD. NAZRUL ISLAM KHAN

Django Developer

Summary

Django developer with 1.5+ years of experience in building and maintaining high-traffic web applications. Proven ability to design, develop, and deploy Django applications using a variety of technologies, including Python, Redis, and PostgreSQL. Strong understanding of Django's core concepts and features, as well as its best practices.

Experience

* Backend Developer - Django (Junior)

September 2022 - Present

Care-Box Limited, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Responsibilities:

- Utilize existing system with Redis and WebSocket.
- Develop Inventory System for existing E-commerce.
- Develop POS (Point Of Sale) System for existing E-commerce.
- Develop RFID Project For Singapore Govt.
- Live Doctor Consultation System With Prescription.
- Implemented CI/CD Pipeline.

* Backend Developer - Django (Intern)

July 2022 – September 2022

Care-Box Limited, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Responsibilities:

- Create API with DRF (Django Rest Framework).
- Develop E-commerce system as a team member.
- Collaborate with Frontend developers for better performance.

* Backend Developer - Django (Intern)

May 2022 – June 2022

Developer Experience Hub, Rajshahi, Bangladesh

Responsibilities:

- Utilize Python and Django to design GraphQL API.
- Maintenance & troubleshooting Django projects.
- Develop Multivendor Dental management system.
- Collaborate with other developers for complicated issues.
- Developed Dental & Patient management system.

* IT Executive

February 2018 – February 2020 Gradient IT Solutions, Uttara, Dhaka

Responsibilities:

- Customer Support.
- Hardware and Software Install and Support.
- · Email Server Installation and Configuration .
- · Domain and Hosting Support.

Projects

- Ecommerce System With POS, Inventory and Warehouse Management.
- Live Doctor Consultation System With Digital Prescription.
- RBITS PUB RFID Project for Singapore Government.
- Hotel Room Rent with multi agent system.
- Dental Multivendor and patient management using GraphQL API.
- SSLCommerz Payment package for python 3.8+ (pysslcmz)